

Oscar Lagatta

SENIOR REACT DEVELOPER AND LEAD ANGULAR DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

Senior React Developer and Lead Angular Developer with a comprehensive understanding of React and Angular ecosystems. Experience in developing and maintaining complex applications leveraging technologies such as Redux Toolkit, Tailwind, Formik, React Query, Angular Material, NX extensions, and Angular-CLI.

PERSONAL DETAILS

- London, United Kingdom
- oscarlagatta@gmail.com
- 07557476002
- https://uk.linkedin.com/in/oscarlagatta-56272246

EXPERIENCE

Whistl

REACT SENIOR DEVELOPER

Feb 2024 – Present

mail delivery system for a high-volume warehouse, significantly enhancing operational efficiencies. • Architecting and managing the full lifecycle development of multiple enterprise-scale

• Leading the redevelopment and optimisation of the front-office order management and

- internal applications using React 16 and 18, demonstrating deep expertise in modern frontend technologies.
- Optimising data management processes by leveraging React Query for efficient data fetching, caching, and state synchronisation, significantly reducing load times and server overhead.
- Implementing advanced user interaction and validation mechanisms using Formik, achieving robust data integrity and improved user experience across all platforms.
- Optimizing data management processes by leveraging React Query for efficient data fetching, caching, and state synchronisation, significantly reducing load times and server overhead.

London Stock Exchange Group

ANGULAR TECHNICAL LEAD

May 2023 – Feb 2024

- Guided the migration of a Silverlight application to Angular using Angular 16 and NX extensions
- Worked with UI frameworks like PrimeNG, Angular Material, and DevExtreme for Angular Proficient in TypeScript, NGRX, and RXJS for robust application development
- Extensive experience with testing frameworks such as Playwright and Cucumber

Turner & Townsend

FRONT-END SENIOR DEVELOPER

September 2022 – March 2023

- Developed internal applications with Angular 14, NX extensions, Angular CLI, and Monorepo architecture
- Leveraged Angular Material, TypeScript, NGRX, and RXJS to deliver robust frontend solutions
- Employed advanced Testing Frameworks like Cypress, Playwright, and Cucumber for reliability and quality assurance

Marks & Spencer

FRONT-END TECHNICAL LEAD

September 2021 – September 2022

- Spearheaded the development initiatives for internal applications tailored to the Sparks and Loyalty departments
- Utilized Angular, NX extensions, Monorepo architecture, TypeScript, Azure CI/CD, and GIT Source Control

Homes England

FRONT-END ANGULAR SPECIALIST

July 2020 – September 2021

- Led the development of public-facing and client internal-facing applications dedicated to supporting HELP TO BUY and Affordable Housing initiatives
- Technology Stack: Angular 11, NX extensions, Angular CLI, Angular Material, SSR Angular Universal, Gov UK Frontend, TypeScript, C#, Terraform, Azure CI/CD, GIT Source Control

Version1

LEAD ANGULAR DEVELOPER

March 2020 – June 2020

- Led the development efforts for the Children and Family Court Advisory and Support Services (Cafcass)
- Technology Stack: Angular 9/10, NX extensions, Angular CLI, Angular Material, TypeScript, Azure CI/CD, GIT Source Control

Jato Dynamics

FULL STACK ANGULAR DEVELOPER - CONTRACTOR

February 2019 – March 2020

- Drove the development and enhancement of pivotal products in the Automotive Industry
- Led the development of JATO.NET, JATO Carspecs, and JATO NEWS Technology Stack: Angular 8, Angular CLI, Angular Material, TypeScript, Cypress, NGRX,
- C#, Azure CI/CD, GIT Source Control

Department for Education

FULL STACK SENIOR DEVELOPER - CONTRACTOR

June 2018 – February 2019

- Led the end-to-end development of the Gender Pay Gap project • Tech Stack: Selenium, Specflow, .NET Core, Angular, ASP.NET, Azure, GIT Source Control

Universal Music Group ANGULAR 5 – C# FULL STACK SENIOR DEVELOPER -

CONTRACTOR

Pioneered the development of an advanced music tagging system

November 2017 – June 2018

- Tech Stack: Angular 5, Angular-CLI, Angular Material, C# ASP.NET core, Teamcity,
- Octopus

Execview

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

June 2017 – November 2017 Maintained and developed new features for the existing portfolio and project

- management application Tech Stack: ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET WebAPI, KnockoutJS, BDD with Specflow,
- SQL Server, Team City, Teamcity, Octopus, NodeJS, HapiJS, GIT

Harvey Nichols

SENIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER/ANALYST

May 2015 – May 2017

- Developed internal web applications for the customer order fulfillment process using Angular 2 / TypeScript / Prime Ng Components
- Translated user requirements into functional design specifications and business process documentation

Turn2Us/ Elizabeth Finn Care

SENIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER • Developed the Benefits Calculator application using C#, ASP.NET, MVC, SQL Server, and

June 2013 – May 2015

BDD with Specflow and Selenium

EDUCATION

CAECE University

INFORMATION SYSTEMS

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION IN MANAGEMENT

1995 - 1999

SKILLS

GIT	CI/CD	SQL Server
Terraform	ASP.Net	C#
Typescript	Angular Material	NX (Narwhal Extensions)
React Query	Formik	Tailwind CSS
Redux Toolkit	Angular	React
Formik		